Jo Ann Meadows Papers
State University of New York at Oswego
Jo Ann Meadows Papers
1969 - 1995
Personal records of SUNY Oswego athletic coach and professor Jo Ann Meadows.
3 linear feet.
Jo Ann Meadows
State University of New York at Oswego Penfield Library 7060 State Route 104 Oswego, New York 13126-3599
2000.003.0001
Collection is open for research.
Jo Ann Meadows was born in 1940 and grew up in Middletown, Ohio. She received a BS in Health & Physical Education from Bowling Green, Ohio, and a Master's degree in Physical Education from Smith College. She holds a National Honorary Basketball Officials Rating. She taught at Douglas College, New Brunswick, NJ from 1965-70. She joined the SUNY Oswego faculty in 1970 and retired in 2000. From 1970-86 she was the women's baskeball coach; from 1973-91 she was the women's athletic director; from 1991-93 she was an assistant athletic director. She was also an Associate Professor of Health and Physical Education. From 1991-92 she was the President of the SUNY Athletic Conference.
In 1991, she and another women's athletic coach filed a Title XI suit against the college. It was dismissed in 1994 after a jury trial.
Smouse, Patricia; State University College (Oswego, N.Y.); Oswego (N.Y.); Stanley, Deborah F.; Weber, Stephen L.; Women's rights; Women college students; Athletes -- New York -- Oswego; Basketball -- New York -- Oswego; Health, Physical Education and Athletics Department; Judicial proceedings; Physical Education -- New York -- Oswego; Students -- New York -- Oswego; Sports
Includes memos, correspondence, staff reviews, team and individual women's sports statistics, suit filed under Title XI, Women's Varsity Sports Organization, women's athletics budgets & sports schedules, women's basketball scorebooks & yearbooks, athletics department administrative records.
- Undergraduate enrollment, 1990 - 1994 (Box-folder 01-01)
  Lists number and percentages of undergraduates for each year, by males and females.
- Athletic Advisory Committee, 1973 - 1977 (Box-folder 01-02)
  Minutes of the Athletic Advisory Committee meetings, memos, letters.
- Athletic Advisory Committee, 1977 - 1983 (Box-folder 01-03)
  Minutes, letters, memos; Policy & Procedures Manual Governing Intercollegiate Athletics, revised 1977, reviewed 1980-81.
- Women's sports: budget summaries, 1969 - 1974 (Box-folder 01-04)
  Women's Varsity Sports Organization (WVSO) budget requests and summaries; some with notations.
- WVSO Budget summaries, 1974 - 1977 (Box-folder 01-05)
  Budget requests, changes, summaries for each academic year. Includes men's intercollegiate athletic budgets for 1974-75, 1975-76, and Student Assoc. Annual Budget for 1975-76.
- WVSO budget summaries, 1977 - 1980 (Box-folder 01-06)
  Budget requests, changes, summaries for academic years. Includes Men's Intercollegiate Athletic Assoc budget for 1977-78, 1979-80 Student Assoc. budget for 1978-79.
- WVSO budget summaries, 1980 - 1985 (Box-folder 01-07)
  Budget requests, changes, summaries. Includes Men's Intercollegiate Athletics budgets for 1980-81, 1981-82, 1982-83, 1983-84, 1984-85.
- Athletics budgets, 1985 - 1989 (Box-folder 01-08)
  WVSO and men's athletics budget requests, summaries; letters to and from Student Assoc. Budget Council.
- Athletics budgets, 1989 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-09)
  Letters, budget requests and changes, summaries.
- Athletics budgets, 1991 - 1993 (Box-folder 01-10)
- Athletics funding, 1989 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-11)
  Ticket sales reports, Cut-a-thon proposal and thank-you letters, invitation to 1991 Alumni Awards Luncheon.
- Athletics budget requests, 1989 - 1992 (Box-folder 01-12)
  Intercollegiate athletic budget requests, summaries, account expenditures.
- IFR balance sheet, 1992 (Box-folder 01-13)
  Computer printout with explanation sheet..
- Athletics fees, 1981 - 1993 (Box-folder 01-14)
  Letters, fee requests, fee referendum fact sheet, information on athletic fees at other SUNY colleges.
- Budget guidelines, 1988 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-15)
  Letters from SUNY officers, SUCO officers, budget reports, policies on cash advances, travel guidelines.
- Women's Sports: Budgets, 1990 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-16)
  Budgets and accounts, letters.
- Women's Issues, Affirmative Action, 1977 - 1984 (01-17)
  Events' planning, bibliographies of Penfield resources on several women's issues, sexual harassment policy statement, women's caucus.
- Women's Studies Assoc. meeting, 1985 (Box-folder 01-18)
  Planning & evaluating the weekend conference, list of attendees statewide, financial data, folder handed to attendees.
- Athletic Dept. consultants' report, 1991 (Box-folder 01-19)
  Consultants' schedule & resumes, their 10-page report after evaluating the athletic, phys. ed. and intramurals on campus.
- Physical Education/Athletics Plan, 1990 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-20)
  Articles, reports on status of women's athletics & sports, graphs of campus building use and faculty stats, "Confidential Comments" from evaluators, proposed plan for change.
- Title XI issues, 1975 - 1992 (Box-folder 01-21)
  NCAA reports, compliance; Title XI evaluations, 1975 regulations; minutes of Health & Phys. Ed. staff meetings re: Title XI compliance.
- Title XI litigation, 1991 - 1995 (Box-folder 01-22)
  Newspaper articles, letters re: sex discrimination suit against SUNY-Oswego by women's athletics coaches Jo Meadows and Patricia Smouse.
- Athletics/Phys. Ed. Depts. structure, 1973 - 1983 (Box-folder 01-23)
  Consultants' and provost's task force reports, ideas for reorganizing the departments, memos from and to department staff.
- Health, Phys. Ed. & Athletic Depts., 1976 - 1979 (Box-folder 01-24)
  Memos on staffing, adding other sports, women's sports coaching staff.
- Athletic & Health Depts. structure, 1990 - 1995 (Box-folder 01-25)
  Reports, newspaper clippings, staff & their assignments, proposed plan for reorganization, memos.
- Health & Phys. Ed. survey reports, 1983 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-26)
  1989 report on athletic survey of SUNYAC colleges, 1991 report on various matters in SUNYAC colleges' athletics departments; memos.
- Athletic Dept. structure, 1981 - 1991 (Box-folder 01-27)
  1983 Health & Physical Education Proposal, departmental memos, course descriptions, athletic staff at other SUNY colleges.
- Physical Education Task Force, 1973 - 1983 (Box-folder 01-28)
  Recommendations for change, 1973 report on intercollegiate athletics for men and women at SUCO, proposals for reorganization of athletic departments.
- Data for program analysis of HPE Depts., 1991 (Box-folder 01-29)
  Submitted by department staff; includes staff performance requirements, handouts to students at the beginning of the year, "1990-91 NCAA Guide for the College-Bound Student-Athlete," departmental forms and memos.
- Athletic coaching loads, 1985 - 1987 (Box-folder 01-30)
  Memos, schedules, 1985 report on HPE coaching loads
- NCAA self- study, 1989 (Box-folder 01-31)
  1989 final report on this departmental study, recommendations, memos.
- Letters from parents, 1980 - 1987 (Box-folder 02-01)
  Complaint letters from parents, replies by staff.
- Athletes--special admit, tutoring, 1985 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-02)
  Sports & staff schedules, students tutored, their GPAs
- Conditions of tennis courts, 1985 - 1991 (Box-folder 02-03)
  Memos, reports, plans to improve campus tennis courts.
- Athletics transportation, 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 02-04)
  Bid specs for athletics bus transportation, charter bus & van schedules, departmental memos.
- Women's athletics: January Intersession, 1991 - 1993 (Box-folder 02-05)
  Information for athletes staying on-campus in January.
- Athletics curriculum committee, 1973 - 1976 (Box-folder 02-06)
  Intercollegiate athletics rationales and requirements, guidelines; constittution of campus Men's Intercollegiate Athletic Association
- SUCO Strategic Plan, 1994 - 2000 (Box-folder 02-07)
  Report & recommendations from the faculty Long Range Plannning Coordinating Committee for various campus activities.
- Save Lee Hall recommendations, 1983 (Box-folder 02-08)
  Various recommendations.
- Athletics--Policies, 1967 - 1989 (Box-folder 02-09)
  Oswego's Intercollegiate Athletics policies & procedures, 1969-70; other policies regarding athletic tickets, post season competition, women playing on men's teams.
- Women's Varsity Alumni Association, 1977 - 1989 (Box-folder 02-10)
  Financial ledger pages, 1984-89; alumni assoc. quarterly statements, receipts, letters, memos
- Women's sports: correspondence, 1984 - 1991 (Box-folder 02-11)
  Various intra-college letters, memos regarding men's and women's athletics.
- Women's Varsity Sports, 1984 - 1985 (Box-folder 02-12)
  Reports & statistics regarding the history of women's varsity sports at Oswego.
- Sports programs, 1973 - 1988 (Box-folder 02-13)
  Letters, memos about changes/additions/eliminations to the varsity sports programs for men and women.
- Lakers sports logo, 1987 - 1988 (Box-folder 02-14)
  Drawings of the sports seagull logo for each varsity sport, some in color.
- Women's Athletics--beginning of the year packet, 1990 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-15)
  Forms, brochures, schedules, finances, other information given to students and coaches at the beginning of the semesters.
- Sports information for freshmen & transfers, 1980 - 1989 (Box-folder 02-16)
  Athletics' schedules, other helpful information
- Women's sports awards & honors, 1984 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-17)
  NCAA Woman of the Year Award, scholar-athlete awards, NYSWCAA award information, 1983 program of the Spring Honors Convocation, The Oswegonian Player of the Week.
- Sports information, 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-18)
  Game results, sports info media contact sheet, copies of newspaper clippings, articles sent to media, 1991 program from SUNY Athletic Conference at Oswego
- Sports information, 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-19)
  Articles sent to media, clippings, scores, statistics of Oswego & SUNYAC teams.
- Women's sports--newspaper articles, 1969 - 1971 (Box-folder 02-20)
  Articles from the women's sports dept. to The Oswegonian, Palladium-Times, the Ontarion with scores, schedules, team information.
- Sports schedules, 1990 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-21)
  Intercollegiate men's and women's schedules.
- Oswego Varsity Sports Foundation newsletter, 1980 - 1982 (Box-folder 02-22)
  Three "newsletters" from the newly-created Oswego sports foundation to support the women's varsity sports program.
- Women's Sports Foundation Constitution, 1979 (Box-folder 02-23)
  First constitution, naming the ex-officio and charter members.
- Women's Athletics Foundation accounts, 1989 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-24)
  Receipts, account ledger pages, copies of vouchers, quarterly financial reports, memos.
- Women's Varsity Sports Organization, 1969 - 1988 (Box-folder 02-25)
  Background of WVSO, several iterations of their constitution, WVSO newsletters.
- Women's Varsity Sports Organization minutes, 1970 - 1980 (Box-folder 02-26)
  Minutes of the Executive Council meetings, 1970 WVSO brochure listing fall intercollegiate women's sports schedules.
- WVSO schedules, brochures, banquet, 1969 - 1988 (Box-folder 02-27)
  1980-81 First Annual WVSO Banquet program; various brochures and schedules for women's athletics.
- WVSO, 1969 - 1979 (Box-folder 02-28)
  Memos, intercollegiate results & schedules, 1972 program for field hockey tournament at Ithaca.
- WVSO minutes, formation, 1972 - 1974 (Box-folder 02-29)
  Meeting minutes, constitution, responsibilities, Executive Council.
- Athletics administrative director's search, 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-30)
- Women's sports staff--hiring procedures, 1972 - 1989 (Box-folder 02-31)
  1989 SUNY brochure on evaluating & promoting professional employees, memos on faculty & coaching appointments, hiring guidelines, position descriptions & qualifications
- Women's sports coaches, 1987 - 1988 (Box-folder 02-32)
  Memos & appointment letters about sports coaching personnel.
- Women's sports assistant coaches, 1984 - 1990 (Box-folder 02-33)
  Memos, letters about coaches, stipends or lack of.
- Womens sports--athletic trainers, 1974 - 1991 (Box-folder 02-34)
  Memos, questionnaires, job descriptions & evaluations, schedules, letters requesting a certain trainer be rehired.
- Women's sports: coaching complaints, 1977 - 1991 (Box-folder 02-35)
  Letters, articles about coaching complaints at Oswego and other colleges.
- Women's sports staff criteria & evaluation, 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-36)
  Athletic director job description & performance review, staff evaluation forms & performance review criteria.
- Women's sports staff performance evaluations, 1989 - 1992 (Box-folder 02-37)
  Forms, criteria for evaluation, memos
- Women's varsity sports annual summaries, 1971 - 1981 (Box-folder 02-38)
  Scores, statistics, team rosters for intercollegiate women's sports.
- Women's sports annual summaries, 1969 - 1972 (Box-folder 02-39)
  Scores, stats, teams for intercollegiate sports; letters regarding athletic competitions.
- Women's sports annual reports, 1972 - 1975 (Box-folder 02-40)
  Sports evaluations, team & individual stats, team rosters.
- Women's sports annual reports, 1977 - 1979 (Box-folder 02-41)
  Scores, stats, team rosters for each varsity sport.
- Women's hockey, 1979 - 1982 (Box-folder 02-42)
  Memos about departmental matters, problems scheduling practices; playing schedules.
- Women's EAIAW Volleyball Tournament, 1977 (Box-folder 02-43)
  Organization & planning for this intercollegiate meet at Oswego; final report & letters of thanks & commendation; mock-up of tournament program.
- Women's NYSAIAW Softball Championship, 1984 (Box-folder 02-44)
  Organization of the tournament at Oswego; all-championship team roster; letters regarding a protest; thank you letters.
- SUNYAC Women's Swimming & Diving Championships, 1991 (Box-folder 02-45)
  Programs for the championships held at Oswego, schedules, team rosters & results, financial reports, planning.
- SUNYAC Cross-Country Championships, Basketball Tournament, 1991 (Box-folder 02-46)
  Planning, financial reports, memos.
- Women's Soccer Championship, 1989 - 1991 (Box-folder 02-47)
  Financial report to ECAC, planning notes, payment vouchers.
- Women's basketball individual career stats, A-K, 1970 - 1988 (Box-folder 02-48)
  Arranged alphabetically, covering many seasons of play, listing each school year and the individual's statistics.
- Women's basketball individual career stats, L-Z, 1970 - 1987 (Box-folder 02-49)
  Arranged alphabetically, listing each player and her statistics in many categories.
- Women's basketball individual records, 1981 - 1991 (Box-folder 02-50)
  Team rosters and stats.
- Women's basketball records, 1975 - 1977 (Box-folder 02-51)
  Scoresheets list individual and team accumulative records.
- Women's basketball records, 1977 - 1979 (Box-folder 02-52)
- Women's basketball practices, 1978 - 1979 (Box-folder 03-01)
  Outlines of team practices & conditioning exercises, some rosters.
- Women's basketball practices, 1980 - 1982 (Box-folder 03-02)
  Practice schedules, outlines, conditioning exercises; day by day notes.
- Women's basketball practices, 1982 - 1984 (Box-folder 03-03)
  Day to day lists of practice schedules, conditioning exercises.
- Women's basketball score book, 1970 - 1971 (Box-folder 03-04)
  Official score book.
- Women's basketball official scorebooks, 1970 - 1976 (Box-folder 03-05)
  Arranged by semester.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1976 - 1978 (Box-folder 03-06)
  Scorebooks for the 1976-77 and 1977-78 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1978 - 1980 (Box-folder 03-07)
  Scorebooks for the 1978-79 and 1979-80 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1980 - 1982 (Box-folder 03-08)
  Scorebooks for the 1980-81 and 1981-82 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1982 - 1983 (Box-folder 03-09)
  Scorebook for 1982-83 season.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1983 - 1985 (Box-folder 03-10)
  Scorebooks for the 1983-84 and 1984-85 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1985 - 1987 (Box-folder 03-11)
  Scorebooks for the 1985-86 and 1986-87 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1987 - 1990 (Box-folder 03-12)
  Scorebooks for the 1987-88, 1988-89, and 1989-1990 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, 1990 - 1992 (Box-folder 03-13)
  Scorebooks for the 1990-91 and 1991-92 seasons.
- Women's Basketball Official Scorebook, season stats, 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 03-14)
  Scorebook for the 1992-93 season; printout of women's basketball 1992-93 season statistics.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1980 - 1981 (Box-folder 03-15)
  Yearbook includes copies of newspaper clippings about the games, and individual women's basketball records from 1970-80 for Oswego and their opponents.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1981 - 1982 (Box-folder 03-16)
  Copies of newspaper clippings about team members, and the games played. Includes a color photo of the basketball team, with Laker seagull mascot.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1982 - 1983 (Box-folder 03-17)
  Copies of newspaper clippings of the games; individual and team statistics. Includes black and white photo of the team.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1983 - 1984 (Box-folder 03-18)
  Copies of newspaper clippings about the games; individual and team statistics. Includes black and white team photo.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1984 - 1985 (Box-folder 03-19)
  Copies of newspaper clippings about the team, games; individual and team statistics.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1985 - 1986 (Box-folder 03-20)
  Copies of newspaper clippings about the team and games; individual and team statistics.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1986 - 1987 (Box-folder 03-21)
  Copies of newspaper clippings about the team and players; individual and team statistics.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1987 - 1988 (Box-folder 03-22)
  Copies of newspaper clippings about the games and players; individual and team statistics.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1988 - 1989 (Box-folder 03-23)
  Copies of newspaper clippings; individual and team statistics.
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1989 - 1990 (Box-folder 03-24)
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1990 - 1991 (Box-folder 03-25)
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 03-26)
- Women's basketball yearbook, 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 03-27)